





aunik43@gmail.com



in/tahmidanik



github.com/tahmidsparrow

Dhaka, Bangladesh



www.tahmidulabedin.me

SUMMARY

Dedicated, flexible, and competent Software Developer with over nine years of experience both in local and offshore industries with designing and developing SharePoint/software/web applications according to client needs. Expertise in debugging, troubleshooting, and executing application programs to make sure it delivers expected output. Capable of creating technical documentation and liaising with developer team to complete projects on time. Certified professional with excellent communication skills. Well experienced in agile development methodology and project planning through IIRA.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- SharePoint Online Modern, SharePoint Online Classic, SharePoint 2013, SharePoint 2010.
- Power Platform Power Apps, Power Automate, Power Pages, Power Platform Solution.
- Azure Logic app, Functions, App Services, WebJobs, Storage Account, Azure AD App, Service Bus, Azure Key Vault
- SharePoint Framework (SPFx), SharePoint Apps, CSOM, PnP, JSOM, Graph API
- SharePoint Event Receiver, Remote Event Receiver (Online), SharePoint Timer Job, Remote Timer Job (Online)
- ASP.Net MVC, ASP.Net Web Form, ASP.Net Web API.
- MS SQL Servers, MySQL, LINQ, Entity Framework
- WPF, WinForms
- Typescript, React, Angular JS, jQuery.
- Gulp, WebPack
- Bootstrap, Fluent UI, SCSS
- SharePoint Designer, InfoPath, Microsoft Lists, Microsoft Forms
- ShareGate, SharePoint Migration Tool (SPMT)
- SharePoint designer's workflow (2010, 2013)
- PowerShell, SharePoint Online Management Shell, CSOM, PnP
- Github, SVN, Git
- Jira, Trello, Desk Time
- VS Code, Visual Studio

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- C# Corner MVP, 2020 Awarded. Url: www.csharpcorner.com/members/tahmidul-abedin
- President, Kolpojontro Foundation. Url: www.kolpojontro.org
- Skilled in Technical Speaking in both corporate training and community seminar & workshop. Url: www.youtube.com/@TahmidAnik12
- Technical Writing on community platforms: <u>C# Corner</u>, <u>Code Project</u>

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal Software Engineer (March 2023 - Continue) Genweb2 Limited - Dhaka, Bangladesh.

- Understand, prepare, and present solutions to customers that address complex issues.
- Lead a team of 6 developers.
- Migrated SPO Classic to Modern.
- Migrated SPO Workflow to Power Automate.
- Developed Power Platform application using the solution and deployed with different environment (dev, stage, Prod).
- Responsible for architecture, design, and development of applications and services using Microsoft SharePoint, Office 365, and Microsoft .NET technologies.
- Involved in development of a computer vision-based solution (SD-17) for converting Bangla sign language to standard Bangla text and converting Bangla Unicode text to Bangla animated sign puppet which is a government project of Bangladesh.

Senior Software Engineer (Jan 2019 – Feb 2023) **Genweb2 Limited –** Dhaka, Bangladesh.

- Migrated SharePoint On-prem to Online using Sharegate.
- Developed Power Platform applications utilizing Solution and Environment features for better deployment management.
- Prepared technical documentations e.g., Technical Design Document, Business Requirements Document, Test Cases, Release Document, Deployment Document.
- Reviewing code, sign off code for push to production.

Software Engineer (January 2017 – December 2018) **Genweb2 Limited** – Dhaka, Bangladesh.

- Developed and designed solutions using SPFx for SharePoint, Teams, and O365.
- Developed web applications using ASP.Net MVC and Entity Framework.
- Trained and mentored junior developers and engineers to improve overall team performance.
- Prepared technical documentations e.g., Technical Design Document, Business Requirements Document, Test Cases, Release Document, Deployment Document.
- Reviewing code, sign off code for push to production.

Junior Software Engineer (Feb 2016 – Dec,2016) **Thakral Information Systems Pvt. Ltd.** - Dhaka, Bangladesh.

CERTIFICATIONS

- MS Exam 70-487: Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services.
- MS Exam 70-488: Developing Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013 Core Solutions.
- MS Exam 70-486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications.
- MS Exam 70-480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering 3.76 out of 4 American International University-Bangladesh Feb, 2016

LANGUAGES

Bengali: Native language

English: Fluent

- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and fastpaced atmosphere.
- Designed and developed SharePoint on premise solutions for both SharePoint on premise and online which includes SharePoint web part, event receiver, timer job and SharePoint workflows.
- Managed and maintained client's SharePoint environment.
- Developed and maintained courteous and effective working relationships.
- Ensured high-quality code by using pair programming approach.

OFFSHORE POSITIONS

SharePoint Consultant (January 2017 – January 2024) **Cadence Design Systems** - San Jose, California, U.S. [Contact, Offshore office from Genwen2 Limited]

- Developed and maintained SharePoint solutions using SPFx with Typescript, React, AngularJS, Rest API, Graph API, and ISOM
- Developed SharePoint Remote Event Receivers (for Online), Remote Timer Jobs (using Azure WebJobs) using managed CSOM with PnP.
- Developed solutions using Power Apps, Power Platform.
- Automated processes using SharePoint workflow, PowerShell, and Power Automate.
- Migrated more than 150+ SharePoint on premise sites to online using ShareGate, PowerShell, and custom solutions (for migrating InfoPath forms).
- Converted (Modernized) classic SharePoint teams sites to modern teams and communication sites using PowerShell (PnP, CSOM), and .net (CSOM and PnP).

Software Developer (June 2024 - Continue)

Crownpeak - Denver, Colorado, U.S.

[Contact, Offshore office from Genwen2 Limited]

- Developed, and maintained, new features and enhancements for an ASP.NET-based enterprise web content management system (DXM).
- Analyzed client-reported issues, debugged the application to identify root causes, and implemented appropriate solutions.
- Collaborated effectively with a cross-functional team distributed across multiple time zones.